Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Katherine.
我是Katherine。
And today at EnglishPod, we have a lesson for you about small talk.
今天在EnglishPod，我们为大家准备了一节关于闲聊的课程。
That's right.
没错。
We continue with our series about short casual conversations you may have with your friends,
我们继续这个系列，内容是关于你和朋友、
somebody you haven't seen in a long time, or maybe even a co-worker.
很久没见的人，甚至可能是同事之间进行的简短随意对话。
That's right.
没错。
So in today's dialogue, we're going to listen to two people who work in the same building.
所以在今天的对话中，我们会听到两个在同一栋楼工作的人。
They're going to talk a little bit about travel, right Marco?
他们会聊一点旅行的事，对吧，Marco？
Yeah.
是的。
And a little bit about recommending a place to go on vacation, maybe Europe.
还会推荐一个度假的地方，可能是欧洲。
And so we're going to have some great phrases as to speaking of this topic very briefly
我们会学到一些很棒的短语，用来和朋友
with a friend.
简短地聊这个话题。
All right.
好的。
Let's listen to today's dialogue.
让我们来听今天的对话。
Hey, Michelle.
嘿，Michelle。
Good to see you.
很高兴见到你。
Are you at lunch?
你在吃午饭吗？
Oh, hi, Jim.
哦，嗨，Jim。
No, I just got back.
不，我刚回来。
I thought you were on vacation now.
我以为你现在在度假呢。
No, I wish I was.
不，我倒希望是。
I just got back from Spain, actually.
实际上，我刚从西班牙回来。
Oh, wonderful.
哦，太棒了。
Have you been there before or was it your first time?
你以前去过那里，还是这是第一次？
My first time.
第一次。
I've traveled around Europe a lot, but this was my first time to Spain.
我去过欧洲很多地方，但这是第一次去西班牙。
It was amazing and the weather was just beautiful.
太棒了，天气也非常好。
No rain and just sun, sun, sun.
没有下雨，只有阳光、阳光、阳光。
I'm so jealous of you.
我真羡慕你。
I've never been anywhere in Europe.
我从来没去过欧洲任何地方。
I've always dreamed of traveling around and seeing the sights.
我一直梦想着到处旅行，看看风景。
Well, I really recommend Spain.
嗯，我强烈推荐西班牙。
You really should go.
你真应该去。
Anyway, it's been great to catch up, but I must be going.
总之，很高兴能聊一聊，但我得走了。
This is my floor.
我到这层了。
Speak again soon, I hope.
希望很快再聊。
For sure.
当然。
Take care.
保重。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So, now, let's take a look at some of the language on Language Takeaway.
那么，现在让我们看看“语言要点”部分的一些语言点。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right.
好的。
In Language Takeaway, we've got a couple of words and phrases for you.
在“语言要点”中，我们为大家准备了一些单词和短语。
The first one is, I just got back.
第一个是“I just got back”。
So, to get back from somewhere, Marco.
所以，“to get back from somewhere”，Marco。
That's right, Jim.
没错，Jim。
Just got back from Europe.
刚从欧洲回来。
And when you say, I just got back, is I recently or very recently returned from somewhere.
当你说“I just got back”时，意思是我最近或刚刚从某个地方回来。
That's right.
没错。
To get back from somewhere means to return from that place.
“To get back from somewhere”意思是回到那个地方。
So, in this dialogue, Jim just got back from Spain.
所以，在这个对话中，Jim刚从西班牙回来。
Michelle just got back from lunch.
Michelle刚吃完午饭回来。
This means to return from somewhere.
这意思是回到某个地方。
That's right.
没错。
So, it can be a place, not only a country, but it can be, for example, the office.
所以，它可以是一个地方，不只是一个国家，比如也可以是办公室。
I just got back from work.
我刚下班回来。
Or I just got back from football practice.
或者我刚从足球训练回来。
That's why I'm very sweaty.
所以我浑身是汗。
Right.
对。
So, this obviously means that you are now not in the same place where you just got back
所以，这显然意味着你现在不在你刚回来的那个地方。
from.
No, I'm from America.
不，我来自美国。
I went to Spain on vacation and I just got back from Spain.
我去西班牙度假，然后刚从西班牙回来。
That means I'm in America again.
这意味着我又在美国了。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
You're not still in Spain.
你不在西班牙了。
No.
不在了。
All right.
好的。
So, that's for our first word.
这就是我们的第一个词。
Now, let's go on.
现在，我们继续。
And Michelle said, oh, I'm so jealous of you.
Michelle说：“哦，我真羡慕你。”
All right.
好的。
Jealous is an adjective and a very, very common one.
“Jealous”是一个形容词，非常非常常见。
You can use it in many different circumstances.
你可以在很多不同的情况下使用它。
It means to want what someone else has.
它的意思是想要别人拥有的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So, in this case, Michelle is jealous that Jim went on vacation.
所以，在这个例子中，Michelle羡慕Jim去度假了。
So, she wishes she could go on vacation.
所以，她希望自己能去度假。
That's right.
没错。
I'm so jealous of you.
我真羡慕你。
Or if you see someone who has a new pair of shoes and you like the shoes because you don't
或者，如果你看到有人有双新鞋，你喜欢那双鞋，因为你自己没有，
have them, you can say, I'm so jealous.
你可以说，我真羡慕。
I love your shoes.
我喜欢你的鞋子。
That's right.
没错。
And if you're jealous, you say, I am jealous.
如果你感到嫉妒，你就说，我嫉妒。
Or if you're jealous of a person, you say, I am jealous of you.
或者，如果你嫉妒某个人，你就说，我嫉妒你。
And so, they were ending their conversation and Jim said, you know what?
然后，他们结束了对话，吉姆说，你知道吗？
It's been great to catch up with you.
跟你叙叙旧真是太好了。
All right.
好的。
This is a really important phrase, to catch up.
这是一个非常重要的短语，“叙旧”。
It means two different things.
它有两种不同的意思。
And we're going to talk about one meaning here today.
我们今天要讨论其中一种意思。
To catch up with someone, like to talk to them about what they've been doing recently,
“和某人叙旧”，比如和他们聊聊他们最近在做什么，
means to learn about their life because maybe you haven't talked in a long time.
意思是了解他们的生活，因为可能你们很久没说话了。
That's right.
没错。
So, maybe you haven't seen your friend in two years and you go out for dinner to catch
所以，也许你两年没见朋友了，你们出去吃饭叙旧，
up, to talk about what has happened in your life recently.
聊聊你们最近生活中发生了什么。
That's right.
没错。
Or if you see a friend on the street and you know that you haven't seen him or her in a
或者，如果你在街上遇到一个朋友，并且你知道你已经很久没见到他或她了，
long time, you can make a date to catch up.
你可以约个时间叙叙旧。
So, hey Marco, I haven't seen you in months.
所以，嘿，Marco，我好几个月没见到你了。
Let's catch up sometime soon.
我们找个时间聚聚吧。
That's right.
没错。
And that means to share information and to find out how you have been recently.
这意味着分享信息，了解你最近过得怎么样。
Exactly.
正是如此。
All right.
好的。
Now, when he was getting out of the elevator, he said, this is my floor.
现在，当他走出电梯时，他说，这是我到的楼层。
Now, we know floor, but my floor, what is this?
我们知道“楼层”这个词，但“我的楼层”是什么意思？
My floor, your floor, whose floor?
我的楼层，你的楼层，谁的楼层？
Right.
对。
This doesn't make much sense, does it?
这听起来不太合理，对吧？
Well, actually floor here means that this is the floor that I work on or the floor that
嗯，实际上这里的“楼层”指的是我工作的楼层或者
I live on.
我住的楼层。
It means the place I'm going to.
它指的是我要去的地方。
Right.
对。
So, we know floor, the ground beneath our feet in a building.
所以，我们知道“楼层”是指建筑物里脚下的地面。
But in this case, we're talking about one of the levels of a building.
但在这个例子中，我们指的是建筑物的其中一层。
So, maybe the sixth floor.
那么，可能是六楼吧。
That's right.
没错。
So, if I'm in my apartment building in the elevator, I can say, oh, stop the elevator.
所以，如果我在公寓楼的电梯里，我可以说，哦，停一下电梯。
This is my floor.
这是我住的楼层。
I want to get off the elevator.
我想下电梯。
Right.
对。
This is where I live.
这就是我住的地方。
All right.
好的。
So, a lot of great stuff there.
那里有很多好东西。
Why don't we take a break and listen to the dialogue again?
我们休息一下，再听一遍对话怎么样？
Hey, Michelle.
嘿，米歇尔。
Good to see you.
很高兴见到你。
Are you at lunch?
你在吃午饭吗？
Oh, hi, Jim.
哦，嗨，吉姆。
No, I just got back.
不，我刚回来。
I thought you were on vacation now.
我以为你现在在度假呢。
No, I wish I was.
不，我倒希望是。
I just got back from Spain, actually.
实际上，我刚从西班牙回来。
Oh, wonderful.
哦，太棒了。
Have you been there before or was it your first time?
你以前去过那里，还是这是第一次？
My first time.
我的第一次。
I've traveled around Europe a lot, but this is my first time to Spain.
我去过欧洲很多地方，但这是第一次来西班牙。
It was amazing and the weather was just beautiful.
太棒了，天气也特别好。
No rain and just sun, sun, sun.
没下雨，全是太阳、太阳、太阳。
I'm so jealous of you.
我真羡慕你。
I've never been anywhere in Europe.
我从来没去过欧洲任何地方。
I've always dreamed of traveling around and seeing the sights.
我一直梦想着到处旅行，看看风景。
Well, I really recommend Spain.
嗯，我强烈推荐西班牙。
You really should go.
你真应该去。
Anyway, it's been great to catch up, but I must be going.
总之，很高兴能聊聊，但我得走了。
This is my floor.
我到这层了。
Speak again soon, I hope.
希望很快再聊。
For sure.
当然。
Take care.
保重。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So, now let's take a look at four key phrases on Fluency Builder.
那么，现在来看看“流利度构建器”里的四个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
So, there are some keys to these small talk conversations and they are definitely the
所以，这些闲聊对话有一些关键点，它们绝对是
phrases.
短语。
The first one we have here is, good to see you.
我们这里的第一个是，很高兴见到你。
So, Jim says, hey, Michelle, good to see you.
所以，吉姆说，嘿，米歇尔，很高兴见到你。
That's right.
没错。
So, we've chosen this phrase because it's very casual and very common to use as a polite
我们选择这个短语是因为它非常随意，而且常用作一种礼貌的
way of saying, hey, how are you?
方式来说“嘿，你好吗？”
Good to see you.
很高兴见到你。
I'm actually showing you that I'm happy that I am talking to you.
我其实是在向你表示，我很高兴能和你说话。
So, this is a very flexible phrase.
所以，这是一个非常灵活的短语。
You can say it at the beginning of a conversation when you just see someone, hey, Marco, good
你可以在对话开始时刚见到某人时说，嘿，马可，很高兴
to see you.
见到你。
Or at the end, you can say, it was very good to see you.
或者在结束时，你可以说，很高兴见到你。
I hope to see you again soon.
希望很快能再见到你。
That's right.
没错。
So, maybe you can use it at the beginning if you just begin to talk to someone or if
所以，你可以在刚开始和别人说话时用它，或者
you're saying goodbye, you can say, well, you know what?
在告别时，你可以说，嗯，你知道吗？
I have to go now, but it's been good to see you.
我现在得走了，但很高兴见到你。
So, very flexible phrase.
所以，这是一个非常灵活的短语。
That's right.
没错。
Now, when Michelle thought that Jim was on vacation, Jim said, no, no, no.
现在，当米歇尔以为吉姆在度假时，吉姆说，不，不，不。
I wish I was.
我希望我是。
All right.
好吧。
I wish I was.
我希望我是。
I thought you were on vacation.
我以为你在度假。
So, she thought that he was still on vacation in Spain.
所以，她以为他还在西班牙度假。
And he says, well, I'm not because, you know, here I am, but I wish I was.
然后他说，嗯，我不是，因为，你知道，我在这儿，但我希望我是。
I wish I was in Spain right now because Spain is so nice.
我希望我现在在西班牙，因为西班牙太美了。
That's right.
没错。
So, it may seem a little bit strange, but it's actually completing the idea.
所以，这可能看起来有点奇怪，但实际上是在补充完整这个想法。
And basically, we're using the verb to be because that's the question.
基本上，我们用了动词“是”，因为那是问题所在。
Are you on vacation?
你在度假吗？
No, I wish I was on vacation.
不，我希望我在度假。
So, that means he's not, but he wants to be.
所以，这意味着他不是，但他想是。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so now, he actually had to get going and he used this exact phrase.
好的，那么现在，他实际上得走了，他用了这个确切的短语。
He said, I must be going.
他说，我必须走了。
I must be going.
我必须走了。
Now, remember this as a phrase.
现在，记住这是一个短语。
This is a good way to end a conversation.
这是结束对话的好方法。
Maybe you have to go to work.
也许你得去上班。
Maybe you have your kids at home.
也许你的孩子在家。
You have to take them somewhere.
你得带他们去某个地方。
So, you say, I'm really sorry, I must be going, but let's see each other again soon.
所以，你说，真的很抱歉，我必须走了，但我们很快再见面吧。
That's right.
没错。
So, you are politely ending the conversation.
所以，你是在礼貌地结束对话。
You are politely saying, I can't talk to you anymore.
你是在礼貌地说，我不能再和你聊了。
I must be going now, but it's been great to talk to you.
我现在必须走了，但和你聊天很开心。
That's right.
没错。
Very polite.
非常礼貌。
So, remember this one.
所以，记住这个。
It's better than, I'm going now.
这比说“我现在走了”要好。
We don't say that.
我们不会那么说。
Yeah, or I have to go.
是的，或者“我得走了”。
Well, you can say, I have to go, but it's nice saying, oh, you know what?
嗯，你可以说“我得走了”，但说“哦，你知道吗？”更好。
I really like talking to you, but I must be going now.
我真的很喜欢和你聊天，但我现在必须走了。
And Jim also finished by saying, we'll speak again soon.
吉姆最后还说，我们很快再聊。
And Michelle said, for sure.
米歇尔说，当然。
For sure.
当然。
Now, Americans particularly love to say this phrase.
现在，美国人特别喜欢说这个短语。
For sure means yes, or I agree, or definitely.
“当然”意思是“是的”，或者“我同意”，或者“肯定”。
Right.
对。
You can use it as an interjection.
你可以把它用作感叹词。
So, if I say, hey, Catherine, am I going to see you later on today?
所以，如果我说，嘿，凯瑟琳，我今天晚些时候会见到你吗？
Yeah, for sure.
是的，当然。
For sure.
当然。
There we go.
就是这样。
So, you're saying yes, absolutely, definitely, for sure.
所以，你是在说“是的，绝对，肯定，当然”。
So, Marco, my birthday is Friday night.
所以，马可，我的生日是周五晚上。
Are you going to come to the party?
你会来参加派对吗？
For sure.
当然。
I wouldn't miss it for the world.
我绝不会错过。
All right.
好吧。
So, that's all we have for today.
所以，这就是我们今天的内容。
Why don't we review everything we've taken a look at now and listen to the dialogue one
我们为什么不回顾一下我们看过的所有内容，然后最后再听一遍对话
last time.
呢？
Hey, Michelle.
嘿，米歇尔。
Good to see you.
很高兴见到你。
Are you at lunch?
你在吃午饭吗？
Oh, hi, Jim.
哦，嗨，吉姆。
No, I just got back.
不，我刚回来。
I thought you were on vacation now.
我以为你现在在度假。
No, I wish I was.
不，我倒希望我是。
I just got back from Spain, actually.
其实我刚从西班牙回来。
Oh, wonderful.
哦，真棒。
Have you been there before or was it your first time?
你以前去过那里，还是这是第一次？
My first time.
第一次。
I've traveled around Europe a lot, but this was my first time to Spain.
我去过欧洲很多地方，但这是第一次去西班牙。
It was amazing and the weather was just beautiful.
太棒了，天气也特别好。
No rain and just sun, sun, sun.
没下雨，全是太阳、太阳、太阳。
I'm so jealous of you.
我真羡慕你。
I've never been anywhere in Europe.
我从来没去过欧洲任何地方。
I've always dreamed of traveling around and seeing the sights.
我一直梦想着到处旅行，看看风景。
Well, I really recommend Spain.
嗯，我强烈推荐西班牙。
You really should go.
你真该去一趟。
Anyway, it's been great to catch up, but I must be going.
总之，很高兴能聊一聊，但我得走了。
This is my floor.
我到这层了。
Speak again soon, I hope.
希望很快再聊。
For sure.
当然。
Take care.
保重。
All right.
好的。
So, this was another part of our small talk series.
所以，这是我们闲聊系列的另一部分。
As you can see, very short, but very useful language used to talk very briefly with someone.
如你所见，非常简短，但用来跟人简短交谈非常有用。
It always happens.
这种事经常发生。
You meet somebody at the elevator or you just want to talk very quickly.
你在电梯里遇到某人，或者只想快速聊几句。
Yeah, but you don't want to talk about anything that's too personal like someone's politics
是啊，但你不想谈太私人的话题，比如某人的政治观点。
or their religious beliefs or their children because maybe you don't know them very well.
或者他们的宗教信仰、孩子，因为可能你跟他们不太熟。
So, these are really great topics to talk about like business trips or vacation or the
所以，这些是很棒的话题，比如商务旅行、度假。
weather.
或者天气。
English speakers love to talk about these when they don't know someone that well.
英语母语者在跟不太熟的人聊天时喜欢谈这些。
That's right.
没错。
So, if you have any questions or any comments about this lesson or you want to suggest any
所以，如果你对这课有任何问题或评论，或者想建议其他话题。
other topics, you can find us at EnglishPod.com.
你可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
We hope to see you all there.
希望在那里见到大家。
Bye.
再见。
See you guys.
各位再见。
I will see you guys later, take care.
回头见，保重。